

Marco Fink Physiscist / Data Scientist



23 October 1990



Germany



+49 1511 2943669



https://github.com/Nephas



marco.fink@fau.de

About me ——

I put great value in a broad and general knowledge, and try to keep myself educated in a wide range of sciences and arts. I think this is necessary to train independence and critical thinking and to put the narrow theoretical skillsets taught at university to effective and creative use.

In Space science I got involved in complex software projects and learned the importance of clean code and documentation for a team effort from practical experience.

Skills ——

Physics

Computer Science

Math

Teamwork

Scientific Writing

Game Design*1.5 Guitar*2 Martial Arts*2 Painting*2.5 Cooking*2.5

(*)[Skills are measured on a logarithmic scale (from 0 - 6) of hours spent learning and applying.]

[Interests]

Everything that has to do with space, the space industry and widening our understanding of nature and the world around us. More specifically, I am building a skillset of statistical and computational methods to make sense of any type of data and the programming abilities to visualize and automate these analysis processes. From my list of hobbies especially my efforts in video game programming, feed back into my professional skillset.

Education

since 2017 Ph.D. candidate in astrophysics Dr.-Karl-Remeis-Sternwarte Bamberg

2014 - 2016 M.Sc. Physics FAU & Dr.-Karl-Remeis-Sternwarte Bamberg Majoring in X-ray astrophysics

2010 - 2014 B.Sc. Physics FAU Erlangen-Nürnberg Specializing in particle, detector and astrophysics

2000 - 2010 High school Geschwister-Scholl-Gymnasium Röthenbach Specializing in mathematics and physics.

Experience

since 2017	Project Work eROSITA telemetry preprocessing	eROSITA pipeline	
2016-2017	ESA Internship At the Gaia calibration team.	ESAC Madrid	
2015-2016	Master Thesis Data Analysis of a sample of extra	DrKarl-Remeis-Sternwarte Bamberg extragalactic X-ray sources	
2013-2016	Teaching and Research Assistant Data Analysis, scientific computing tion proposals.	FAU & ECAP , tutorial supervision and observa-	

Travels

2017	Euro-SciPy	Erlangen
2017	XMM-Universe	Rome
2016	XMM-Universe	Madrid
2014	Astronomische Gesellschaft	Tübingen

Detailed skills

Languages German, English, Spanish

Programming Object-oriented, Functional and Event-driven;

Python, Java, C++, Octave, Shell, Lisp

Scientific Detector physics, Image Processing, Statistical Methods,

Optimization, Numerical Methods, Databases

Software Unix, LaTeX, SciPy, Git, SQL

Other information

Review

bla bla bla